HERSY GRACE PRE

LICENSED MECHANICAL ENGINEER

Manila, Philippines \cdot +639178394080

hersypre@gmail.com



Growth driven professional with demonstrated history of working in Oil and Gas industry. Implement, optimize industrial processes, forecasting and demand management, provide high quality customer satisfaction, and has experience in developing and testing new procedures to reduce costs and improve production rates. To achieve high career growth and serve the organization with outstanding result.

SKILLS

- Knowledgeable in SAP ECC 6.0
- Basic understanding of the Supply Chain
- Knowledgeable in Macro Programming via Excel VBA
- AutoCAD, Solid edge, SAP, Adobe
- Process improvement and Problem solving
- Microsoft Office Suite

EXPERIENCE:

APRIL 2021 – PRESENT

FLEET PLANNING PROGRAMMER, PETRON CORPORATION

- DEMAND FORECASTING AND SCHEDULING
 - Handled the secondary distribution of fuels for the inventory replenishment of service stations through Expanded Inventory Delivery Driven System (E-IDDS)
 - Leveraged data analytics and advanced forecasting techniques to create an accurate daily demand forecast that enabled efficient planning & deployment for Nationwide (North Luzon, South Luzon, Visayas and Mindanao area) replenishment of fuel each day while meeting customer demands with 98% accuracy rate.
 - Optimized use of LPG trailer fleet to achieve 800MT daily average Luzon interplant replenishment based on consolidated daily LPG stock position report and prior day's actual terminal withdrawal

CUSTOMER SERVICE

- Validated and processed E-IDDS customer interventions to ensure timely deliveries within Petronguidelines, resulting in a 20% decrease of delivery delays.
- Streamlined order processing for 500+ dealerships with an average of 300 sales order per day through developing automated system

MASTER DATA CUSTODIAN

- Maintained master data of E-IDDS tools, including over 500+ Service Station (SS) profiles & characteristics and 200+ tank truck characteristics to optimize fleet planning operations.
- Reviewed inventory stock position report daily of 288 SS for Metro Manila and 247 SS for Mindanao by analyzing actual sales and inventory submitted by E-IDDS customers and identifying gaps between derived market inventory target level versus actual levels.
- Compared historical, actual, and forecasted volume on a regular basis.
- Delivered monthly reports to management on delivery fulfillment, planning area profiles, incident monitoring, truck availability & utilization levels; achieved 98% accuracy in forecasting delivery trends.

STAKEHOLDER MANAGEMENT

- Coordinated with Area Sales Executive (ASEs) and Reseller Coordinators in reconciliation of datasubmission and assisted them on their inquiries on SS inventory positions and forecasting parameters.
- Communicated with Terminal Operations for loading priorities and adjust scheduling to achieve 100% deliveryfulfillment rate
- Worked closely with Supply department regarding replenishments of Luzon LPG load ports to effectively plan interplant deliveries and determine adjustments of supply source plant.
- Collaborated with third-party haulers on optimizing delivery routes and schedules for 124 trucks for Metro Manila, 109 trucks for Mindanao and 38 trucks for Luzon LPG per day.

FLEET UTILIZATION

- Reviewed the utilization report provided by SMC-SL Road Transport to ensure sufficient trucks on their assigned planning area
- Developed & implemented innovative strategies for efficient fleet management, increasing operational efficiency by 10% and reducing costs by 4%.

PROCESS IMPROVEMENT

- Automated data compilation process such as Delivery Fulfillment Report, Delivery Prioritization Report and LPG File Compilation utilizing Power BI, Power Query, VBA, and Dashboards, increasing accuracy by 8%.

SAP KNOWI FDGF

- Managed generation, revision and deletion of sales order using SAP software.
- Skilled in utilizing SAP for data analysis and reporting through extraction of sales order data.
- Experienced in training and mentoring other team members on the use of SAP for sales and distribution processes.

MENTORING

- Responsible for training and onboarding new hires on work procedures and processes especially for North Luzon, South Luzon, Visayas and Mindanao planning area.
- Addressed and identified areas for improvement for new hires by providing them feedback and performance evaluations.

APRIL 2019 - FEBRUARY 2021

PROCESS ENGINEER, TIMEX PHILIPPINES INCORPORATED

- Led a team of 4 technicians in setup, troubleshooting and support for watch piece parts manufacturing.
- Coordinate with the engineering group to provide technical support for New Products and developmental stage of Complex Dials.
- Investigate product and material issues using DOE, process mapping and other tools to solve and analyze problems to devise solutions.
- Planned and developed operational strategies to achieve production and financial objectives.
- Established usage rate for the operating supplies and evaluates piece parts with cost estimation.
- Produced and revised process documents such as FMEA, control plan, check sheets and work instructions.
- Developed documentation, including diagrams, drawings, and specifications, to meet project requirements and regulatory standards.

EDUCATION:

JUNE 2015 - MARCH 2018

BS MECHANICAL ENGINEERING, TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILLIPINES VISAYAS

- 2018 LAUREL WREATH AWARDEE FOR LEADERSHIP
- 2017-2018 ENGINEERING GOVERNOR, UNIVERSITY STUDENT GOVERNMENT

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2014

MECHANICAL ENG'G TECHNOLOGY, TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES VISAYAS